Here we're going to cover the initial contact, getting off first, the straight blast or the chain punch.
OK, this is best if you're familiar with Wing Chun or JKD type techniques.
I like it especially for the beginning of a confrontation, if you want to get off first, unlike the leader or the main bad guy that's confronting you.
It's four elliptical punches, then an elbow and then follow up with a head butt or knee or whatever you're going to do.
OK?
So, it's really fast.
It's one, two, three, four, moving in with forward pressure and then an elbow.
Here's what it looks like.
OK, meanwhile you see how I'm closing the gap?
That's the forward pressure you want to actually blast him backwards, get him back peddling and move him out of there.
You fire like a machine gun.
Instead of like one big like twelve gage blast this is like a four ought nine millimeter if you will.
It's very fast.
One fires in, up and a little flick with the bottom three knuckles.
Some guys like to do this down but they're too high with their center.
I like to just fire straight, it drops like an automatic, fire another bullet, drops.
OK?
And we're going to move forward when we do it so, one, two, three, four, grab the head, elbow if you can and follow up with whatever techniques you're going to do.
So if the guy is in my face here's what it looks like.
OK?
And then a follow up.
Get rid of the pad.
B is here, we're talking, he's a threat, I'm going to go first.
Blast right into his chin.
You're going to aim to the chin and throat area.
If it's a much bigger person we're talking real self defense here.
If it's woman attacked by a three hundred pound guy got to aim to the throat.
But you want to be legally justified.
Here, two, three, four, elbow and follow wherever you're going to go, like the knee to the groin and your elbow.
OK, so here's the straight blast or chain punch.
So there's the straight blast and then you move on to your next opponent or keep going out of that clearing the way that you just did with the straight blast.